[door opens]
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
[screaming] No!
Oh. my God! Oh. God!
No! Please!
- Shh! Enough!
- Ah! No. please!
- Just behave!
- No!
[screaming]
Damn it!
[panting]
Ow!
What the hell. Alice? Oh.
Damn it. Josh!
- Stay in character!
- Well. I'm sorry!
I just didn't expect you
to get so rough!
Is my nose bleeding?
- Ugh. no. it is not bleeding.
- Damn it.
It's definitely gonna bruise.
I have to present
to clients on Monday.
This was a stupid idea.
Let's just forget it.
No. no.
Wait. wait. wait. wait.
I've got this.
Let me try again.
[owl hooting]
I'm gonna ravage you.
Gross.
Well. I'm sorry.
Do not apologize.
[distant scream]
♪
It came from Susan's house.
- Call 911.
- Josh. no.
Let the cops handle it.
Just stay here. okay?
[phone beeps]
♪ ♪
Susan?
Susan!
Are you all right?
If there's anybody in here.
cops are on the way!
♪ ♪
Susan Granwell.
dead in the kitchen.
Must have been a pretty
big donor for the mayor
to ask you all to step in.
They were old friends.
What do we know?
Neighbors heard a commotion
around 11:00 p.m.
One of them came
to check on Susan.
found her bleeding out on
the ground. already deceased.
Preliminary cause of death is
blunt force trauma to the head.
Looks like she got hit
with that cast iron.
Okay. we'll have it sent to
the lab for further processing.
Whose firearm is that?
Registered to the victim.
but CSU didn't recover
any shell casings.
So she wasn't able to fire
it off before she got hit.
That skillet's
a weapon of opportunity.
so it's not premeditated murder.
What. a robbery gone wrong?
She confronted them with a gun.
they retaliated
by grabbing a cast iron?
Maybe.
Nice house. lots of valuables.
Doesn't feel like a break-in.
Only disturbance was in here.
Windows and doors were intact.
Alarm didn't go.
Whoever did this
either had access to the house.
or she let them in.
Looks like a crime of passion.
I have a feeling Susan Granwell
knew her killer.
All right. folks.
last night. Susan Granwell
was attacked and killed
in her home.
a $12 million historically
preserved home in Fieldston.
Susan was a major donor
and confidant of the mayor.
He would like her killer
brought to justice immediately.
Right. hey. have we
notified the family yet?
No... her son Bobby is in Tokyo
with his grandparents.
and because of the time change.
we haven't been able
to reach them.
But by the time I have to
look this boy in the eyes
and tell him his mother is gone.
I would like to have
some real answers for him.
Our team's initial
assessment was that
this looks like
a crime of passion.
so let's talk about
Susan Granwell and anyone
in her life who could have
snapped and killed her.
Right. well. Susan grew up
an Upper East Side socialite.
old money.
Now she's a hotelier
by way of marriage.
Her late husband. Alex. founded
a chain of boutique hotels
called the Granwell Hotels.
They have locations
across the country.
Yeah. Sam and I stayed
at a Granwell once.
They had a pillow menu.
Well. that's not all they got.
Turns out Granwell Hotels
is knee-deep
in a serious labor dispute.
Maintenance
and hospitality workers
have been on strike
for the past three months
with no end in sight.
They claim Susan is
trying to starve them out.
The protests have been peaceful.
but it's getting nasty.
Nasty enough to attack
Susan in her own home?
She thought so.
Susan filed a police report
last week
after a brick was thrown
through her front window.
She blamed her
disgruntled employees.
but the cops weren't able
to ID a suspect.
So the brick was to
scare her into returning
to the negotiating table.
When that didn't work. maybe
they amped up the intimidation.
and it got out of hand.
Who's running this union?
That would be Jeremy Payton.
career labor organizer.
known for running
campaigns of intimidation.
He has threatened multiple times
to burn down
Granwell properties.
Not the type to catch
flies with honey. huh?
Definitely not.
Granwell sent their goons
to rough me up. to silence me.
We're not scared of you!
You hear that. Susan?
You should be scared of us!
Well. he might be a charmer.
but if it walks like a motive
and talks like a motive...
Well. forensics
might back it up.
Yeah?
Report from the crime scene
just landed.
and Jeremy's fingerprints
were found all over it.
- Mm.
- Low lipid oxidation
in the residue suggests
his prints were recent.
- What about the murder weapon?
- Wiped clean.
No fingerprints there.
Well. nice try. Jeremy.
The man was there.
Let's bring him in.
all: Granwell. Granwell.
you can't hide!
We can see your greedy side!
Granwell. Granwell.
you can't hide!
We can see your greedy side!
- Back up. scabs!
Nobody's getting through
this picket line!
Get out of here! Boo!
Scab!
- Excuse me. FBI.
Excuse us.
[indistinct shouting]
Jeremy Payton. how you doing?
FBI.
Why don't we take the
temperature down a little bit?
Law enforcement protecting
the corporate fat cats again!
Why am I not surprised?
No. No. wait.
That's not what's
happening here. okay?
Look. Mr. Payton. we have
a few questions for you.
so why don't you come with us?
Obstructing a federal agent
is a crime. fellas.
So move. Now.
Oh. you don't tell them
what to do. sweetheart.
Sweetheart?
Okay. yeah. no.
that's not gonna work.
Let's go.
You two. step aside.
or you're coming.
Let's go.
Hands behind your back.
See? You see
what they're doing to us?
Don't let these jackboots
take away your voices!
Union strong!
all: Union strong!
You hear that. Susan?
You should be scared...
From the moment I saw you guys.
I knew that this was
what it was about.
That's not what
you were screaming
at your union brethren about.
You wanted them to believe
that we were there
to shut down your picket.
I saw an opportunity
to keep my people angry.
energized. and I took it.
Sure. it was theater.
but so was this.
Nothing I said
on that video was real.
So Granwell Hotels
never sent you
their people to beat you up?
Not physically. but you know.
they've been beating us down
for long enough.
Jeremy. please. stop.
All right? That's enough.
Did you fake these injuries.
file a false police report
blaming Susan Granwell's
private security?
You gotta give them an enemy
to keep them motivated.
So yeah. I had a couple
of my boys rough me up.
Blamed it all on management.
Sounds like a felony.
Well. it worked.
Momentum's on our side now.
So if Susan Granwell is losing.
why'd you pay her a visit?
Your fingerprints.
they're all over Susan's home.
[scoffs]
Doorknobs. kitchen counters.
Question is. are we gonna
find them on Susan's body?
Hold up. her body?
- You killed her.
- Wait. I...
Beat her to death
and then fled. did you not?
- Whoa...
what are you talking about?
No. no. no. no. no. I didn't...
[tense music]
What? No.
No. no. Susie.
That's my Susie.
Your Susie?
- I didn't do this.
I would never.
I mean. we... we couldn't
come out publicly.
but we were in love.
This woman was your sworn enemy.
You trash talked her daily.
For show.
From the second we met at
negotiations. I felt a spark.
We... we were the same. stubborn.
We wanted big things. you know?
We just chose different paths.
But that didn't stop the fates
from bringing us together.
It's a good story. but you know.
you've also proven
that you're a good actor.
It's not acting.
Prove it.
♪ ♪
I proposed. How about that?
With my nan's heirloom ring.
[crying] You can check
the pics on my cell phone.
There's proof there.
I didn't do this!
I...
[door beeps. opens]
♪ ♪
Hey. Take a look at that.
Happy family.
Doesn't mean he's innocent.
though.
No. but his alibi does.
The JOC confirmed
via security cams
that Jeremy was at
the union office
at the time of the murder.
Well. he's also claiming that
the two of them were engaged.
so that would explain
his fingerprints
all over Susan's house.
Yeah. yeah. yeah.
but that engagement ring.
that seems to be missing.
Hmm.
So what. you're saying that this
could be a robbery after all.
and Susan was killed
over a ring?
It's possible. right?
Oh. yeah.
I looked into vintage rings
like this for Nina.
and a rock like that
from the '20s. good clarity.
thing would go for 750K easy.
- Thanks. Elise.
Well. you win.
but by "Price is Right" rules.
Jeremy's insurance policy puts
the ring's value at 800K.
Okay. yeah.
someone might kill over that.
- Yeah. for sure.
- Okay. but Jeremy said
that only the people
in this photo
knew about the engagement.
Well. that's not entirely true.
Someone took this picture.
All right. so according
to Jeremy Payton.
Bobby's private math tutor
took this photo. which means.
if true. this tutor is
the only other person we know
knew our victim
had an $800.000 ring.
- Which is now missing.
- Right.
And Jeremy also said the tutor
had a key to Susan's home.
So that is means.
that is opportunity.
and that's me hoping you
figure out who this tutor is.
Lucas Williams. 18.
lives in Corona
with his dad. Frank.
and younger sister. Faith.
Okay. Ian.
you wanna get up on his phone?
- On it.
- Any criminal history?
- Not even a parking ticket.
- He's an impressive kid.
Was up for the Miller-Dier Prize
in High School Computing
last year.
He's an honor student at the
Augustus School in Manhattan.
Yeah. a Corona kid at
a private fancy school uptown.
Full ride.
need-based scholarship.
Looks like Dad's been unemployed
for a couple years.
Maybe he was sick
of being the poor kid
at the country club school.
Right. saw an opportunity
for a payday.
but then Susan caught him.
And. I mean. yeah. maybe.
Could be my bias
'cause he's my son's age.
but I'm having
a hard time believing
this kid is our killer.
We need to talk to him.
How we doing. Ian?
- His phone is dark.
not just off.
Lucas must have taken
out the battery.
He's savvy.
- Oh.
So he could be trying
to not be found.
Hey. uh. Augusta School
counselor said
Lucas didn't show up today.
And his dad isn't answering.
All right. let's get a team
to Lucas Williams's house.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
Straight ahead.
It's open.
♪ ♪
Bedroom's clear.
OA. I got a body.
♪ ♪
Is it Lucas?
It's Frank Williams.
You think Lucas did all this?
Killed his father?
If he did. it's his
second murder of the day.
♪ ♪
Hey.
Do we have any BOLO hits
on Lucas Williams yet?
Uh. no. no. but Elise
is working on bringing
his sister. Faith. in.
See if he knows
what her brother's up to.
Someone has to.
I mean. 18. no criminal record.
full ride at a great school.
I mean. seemingly happy family.
Maybe I get killing Granwell
for the ring.
Yeah. I don't know.
Why does a kid like this
go that far for cash?
And then go kill his father.
Wait. Ian just sent
an ME prelim over.
and it puts Frank's
time of death
at approximately 28 hours ago.
Okay. meaning
Lucas's father was killed
before Susan Granwell.
Maybe Lucas.
he kills his dad. and then he...
he needs cash to go on the run.
It's a theory.
I don't know. there's just
something big
we're missing here.
Hey. did you track
down the sister?
Not exactly.
Spoke to Faith's school admin.
She didn't come in today.
We pinged her phone
to the family home.
She left it behind.
You're saying Faith Williams
appears to be missing?
All right.
put out an Amber Alert.
Look. we don't know
if Faith is an accomplice
or a hostage yet. but if she's
with Lucas. she's in danger.
Okay. we got
a BOLO hit on Lucas.
NYPD foot patrol lost him
on West Broadway and Prince.
A lot of high-end consignment
stores down there.
Grab Maggie and OA.
We're on it.
[door bell jingles]
Scola and Eva checked
the other two shops.
No sign of Lucas.
Okay.
Excuse me. FBI.
We're looking for this kid.
He might have been
with his sister.
Have you seen him?
Surely have. but he was alone.
Had a gorgeous
'20s vintage piece.
incredible setting.
The clarity on it?
But he couldn't explain
the provenance.
I don't deal with
creatively sourced items.
if you catch my drift.
- No. we get it.
You operate above board.
So how did the conversation end?
I told him he'd have better
luck at the tawdry pawn shop
down the street.
You just missed him.
both:
Thank you.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Maggie. there he is.
- Got him.
♪ ♪
- Hey!
- He made us.
♪ ♪
In pursuit of our suspect.
heading south on Mercer
towards Spring.
♪ ♪
[tires screeching]
[grunting]
Please. no.
Lucas. you're under arrest
for the murder
of Susan Granwell
and Frank Williams.
- Got the ring.
- Please don't do this.
They took my sister.
I was just trying to save her.
They're gonna kill her.
♪ ♪
- Come on.
- No. no!
Please! Don't do this!
They're gonna kill her!
♪ ♪
Who... who took your sister?
I don't know who they are.
but I stole from them.
and they know.
and they're gonna kill her!
- Okay. all right. stop.
Back up. What'd you steal?
Okay. there is this
crypto phishing scam.
I saw it on Reddit.
Idea is. y-you send
fake transfer links
to a ton of people.
Like. "click here to secure
your crypto account"
sort of thing.
And. um.
if someone clicks on one.
then all the crypto
from their digital wallet
gets drained into yours.
- What are you doing. man?
You're a bright kid.
You got a scholarship.
This was not a smart move.
Hey. I know this
is my fault. okay?
I know.
But the phishing scam
was anonymous.
I don't know how they found me.
- Well. they did.
so why would you do this?
I was desperate.
My dad got laid off
a couple years ago.
He hasn't been able
to find work since.
We were gonna lose our house.
Our heat kept getting shut off!
We needed help!
All right. well.
how much help did you need?
Because it must have been
a lot for these people
to come after your family.
I got a couple small bites.
you know.
100 bucks here or there.
But then I got one big hit.
How much?
315.000 in Bitcoin.
I paid off our mortgage.
caught up on all the bills.
I still had. like.
17K left over.
- Okay. Okay.
- I thought I was saving us!
Yeah. well. okay.
So whoever you stole from.
they found you.
[grim music]
When I got home
from school yesterday.
my sister was gone.
and my dad...
They left a phone
in my dad's hand.
and it had a text message.
It said I had to transfer
the Bitcoin that I stole
into their wallet
by 5:00 p.m. today.
or they were going to
kill my sister.
Your sister gets kidnapped
by these unknown people
you robbed. and you didn't
have enough money left over
to pay them back. so that's why
you went to Susan Granwell's?
I remembered that I had a key.
Right. easy access
to a house full of valuables.
and stealing worked once.
But why did you kill Susan...
She wasn't supposed
to be home. okay?
I was just gonna grab stuff
that she wouldn't miss.
But she was there. and...
and I tried to sneak out.
But it was dark. and I tripped.
and she found me.
and she... she had a gun!
All I could think is.
she's gonna shoot me.
and then my sister is gonna die.
So... so I panicked.
I panicked. and I hit her.
- You killed her.
- I didn't mean to.
I didn't.
You still took the ring.
Yes.
To save my sister.
Please.
You gotta find her.
♪ ♪
Please.
♪
All right. folks. listen up.
This is Faith Williams.
Lucas's 15-year-old sister.
and if we believe his story.
Faith is in real danger.
Can we confirm
she's being held for ransom?
We found the burner phone
in Lucas's bag.
There was a ransom text.
- Okay.
We should believe this is real.
Okay. so "Lucas Williams.
we know who you are.
"We know what you did.
"Send the money you stole
to the following wallet address
"by 5:00 p.m. tomorrow.
or your sister dies."
Right.
That QR code does correspond
to a Bitcoin wallet.
Well. that only gives us
a few hours
to find these kidnappers
and save this girl.
I'm guessing
we cannot track the phone
that sent the ransom texts?
- Correct.
Kidnappers must be using
another burner.
All right. all right.
so let's just respond
to the message.
Just open up the line
of communication.
All right.
start the negotiations.
and get proof of life.
That's what
we're looking for here.
Let's see if we can
smoke these guys out.
[chiming]
- [sighs]
- What? No luck?
Phone's off. or they're
in a spot with no signal.
Either way.
they won't see our message
until their phone's back online.
Right. okay. so what
about the wallet address?
Can we track that?
- Tried. but it's brand new.
No activity to exploit.
But I can track the wallet
Lucas initially robbed.
I am assuming they are owned
by the same person.
So if I can trace
that wallet's IP address.
cross-reference it with
other public data...
bingo!
- Yeah?
The wallet Lucas phished
is affiliated
with an exchange account
registered to a Novarin Systems.
- Novarin Systems.
What kind of company is that?
Officially. IT consulting.
but according
to an ongoing RICO
investigation.
Novarin Systems is also
a suspected front
for the New York clan of Bratva.
You're kidding.
This kid accidentally stole
from the Russian mob.
In an absolutely banner
stroke of bad luck.
18-year-old Lucas Williams
unknowingly stole $315.000
from Bratva. the Russian mob.
How did they even know
Lucas was stealing from them?
Yeah. that's... that's
nagging at me too.
We're just getting
into it. so...
We just arrested the boss
of the New York clan
six months ago.
Do we know who is in charge now?
Uh. yeah.
Uh. Elise. how we doing on that?
Uh. yeah. Organized Crime
believe the new head
of the New York clan of Bratva
to be this man.
54 years old. named...
Andrei Ovechkin?
[suspenseful music]
How long has he been
in New York?
Immigration says three months.
I'm guessing
you've heard of him?
[sighs] You could say that.
All right. so. uh.
you remember my old man
used to work for
the State Department. right?
Right.
So he was stationed in Moscow
for a couple years
when I was 12.
I went to the international
school over there.
You wanna take a wild guess
who my best friend was?
Oof.
You were only in Moscow
for two years.
- Yeah.
Yeah. but you know.
Andrei was. you know...
he was like a brother.
Even after my family
moved back to the States.
you know. we talked
as much as we could.
We had a whole plan. you know.
He was gonna move here.
He was gonna stay with me.
We were gonna open up a...
[chuckles]
Private investigator business.
you know. get answers
for people left behind
in the system.
I smuggled a VHS tape
of "Chinatown" into Moscow.
and we used to watch it
all the time.
I kind of had a thing
for '70s noir.
You still in contact with him?
No. I haven't talked to him
since I was 20.
The Soviet Union collapsed.
You know. it was chaos.
He went dark.
Eventually. I found out he
had joined Bratva to survive.
But his name hasn't
popped up in years.
I figured. you know.
he had been killed
with the trajectory he was on.
[sighs] Seems he got
his stars instead.
Well. his tenure as boss
will be short-lived.
I want a full-scale raid
on his base of operations.
We'll force his hand
to give up the girl.
Respectfully. obviously.
Bratva is good for this.
But with Andrei.
if they sent him here
from Moscow.
he means something
to the organization.
and the powers that be are
watching. and he knows that.
All the more reason
for him to make a statement.
No one steals from Bratva
on Andrei Ovechkin's watch.
I don't know.
my gut is just telling me
that's not how he'd handle this.
You know. it's sloppy.
and he's anything but sloppy.
Jubal. an innocent girl's
life is on the line here.
We've gotta have more
than just your gut.
[apprehensive music]
Are you sure you can
be objective here?
- Oh. yeah. yeah. yeah.
No. no. no.
No. my historical knowledge
of Andrei isn't a blind spot.
If anything. it's an asset.
Okay.
How do you feel about paying
an old friend a visit?
♪ ♪
Hi. I'm here
to speak with Andrei.
He's not taking visitors.
[speaking Russian]
That's not how we treat
our friends. is it. Mitya?
Jubal Valentine.
[laughs]
[chuckles]
- All right.
Or I should say. Assistant
Special Agent in Charge. hmm?
- Oh. okay. Yeah.
So you looked me up.
I... I'd be surprised if you had
recognized me that fast.
Your Russian accent
is also memorable.
Okay.
Come.
We have much to discuss.
Yeah.
No clothes.
no weapons. no wires.
If I didn't know any better.
I'd say you don't trust me.
Andrei.
The boy I knew.
the one who referred
to the rules as suggestions.
him. I trusted with my life.
You disappeared on me. man.
[laughs]
What happened. right?
[sighs] Jubal.
please.
[apprehensive music]
I'm not so naive to think
this is a social call.
Yeah. Well. you're right.
Did your men abduct
a 15-year-old girl
named Faith Williams yesterday?
We did not.
I know about
the stolen crypto wallet
that belonged
to the Bratva front.
And you guys have no sympathy
for thieves.
So I am speaking to the FBI.
not my old friend.
We both made choices.
Yeah. we were out some Bitcoin.
but I don't play games
for small prices.
315K. that's not nothing.
To us? Please.
And look at the trouble
it's caused between the FBI.
the online exposure.
Online exposure?
Bratva's shame is now public.
Everyone know
that boy stole from us.
His name.
his address. the amount...
it's all posted online.
So this kid made a fool of you.
and you knew exactly who he was
and where you could find him.
Jubal. anyone knows how much
cash that boy is sitting on.
Why would I do that?
I knew it's gonna be
open season on the boy.
♪ ♪
Andrei was telling you
the truth.
The forum is called
Protect the Block.
referring to the block chain.
So Lucas Williams was doxxed
on this forum.
He was.
The site tracks suspicious
crypto transactions...
anonymously. but I am
working on ID'ing them.
And Cyber Crimes had no idea
about this forum?
We don't have the manpower.
Crypto theft is
the Wild West of cybercrime.
Fitting 'cause
whoever runs this forum
claims to be a white hat hacker.
But this hacker.
he. what. deputized himself?
He thinks they're on
the side of justice.
Yes. if they suspect someone
has stolen Bitcoin
from another wallet.
they expose the thief.
Tagline of the forum is.
"Actions have consequences."
Right. a-and they flagged
Lucas Williams's scam.
posted his address.
photos. all that.
And the exact amount
that he stole.
Okay.
Well. that's an
"X marks the spot"
for any criminal who wants to
grab 315.000 in stolen crypto.
And anyone with an internet
connection can see it.
I guess that's what Andrei meant
when he said it's open season.
I just unmasked our white hat...
Whitney Kabialis. software
developer here in the city.
She might know more.
[door buzzes]
I did nothing wrong.
Doxxing isn't even a crime.
That kid stole the money.
I just caught him
before you did.
No. Whitney. what you did
was set off
a chain of criminal events
that led to two people
being murdered.
including the abduction
of an innocent girl.
Faith Williams is 15.
She had nothing to do with this.
and now her life
is being ransomed
for some stolen Bitcoin.
all thanks to your forum.
- I hope you find the girl.
I really do.
But I am not responsible for
what nutjobs do with my posts.
Legally. that is not true.
You will be charged
with accessory to murder.
kidnapping.
endangerment of a minor.
What is it that you always say?
"Actions have consequences"?
[tense music]
[door buzzes]
- Now a good time?
- It's perfect.
Whitney here was
just about to offer
her full cooperation. right?
Yeah. I'll help.
Terrific.
Meet FBI intelligence
analyst Ian Lim.
He's the one who cracked
your forum security
and identified you.
- Shadow proxy?
Been trying to narrow down
who might have seen your post
with Lucas Williams'
information.
but your site wipes
all incoming IP addresses.
- Yeah. volatile logging.
There is no backup.
You must have the kidnappers'
wallet address. right?
Yes. it was included
in the ransom.
You should be able to ID them
from the previous transactions.
New wallet. never been used.
So they know what they're doing.
What haven't I tried?
We have no other way to track
or even communicate with them.
♪ ♪
This girl's life depends on it.
Sending crypto is
the only real way
to elicit wallet activity.
Wait. I...
sorry.
I'm trying to keep up here.
It sounds like you're saying
the only way
to trace back to the kidnappers
is to actually send the Bitcoin.
Unless...
we drop something else
in their wallet.
♪ ♪
All right. I know I'm still
out here carrying cash.
but I think I understand
enough about crypto
to know you can't send a text
to a wallet address. right?
- Correct.
You can only send crypto.
But I can create
a new digital coin
that we can send
to the kidnappers' wallet.
What. you can just create
a new cryptocurrency?
- Anyone can.
It takes five minutes.
You're out here
printing money. bro.
Yeah. not really.
It'll be valueless.
Just need it to get
the kidnappers' attention.
May I present...
Huh. "Proof of Life First" Coin.
Very smart.
The coin is the message.
and hopefully this will get
them to turn on their burner.
Exactly.
As soon as this coin appears
in the kidnappers' wallet.
it'll tell them
that Lucas is only willing
to pay the ransom
if they prove that his sister
is still alive.
They turn on their burner
to send proof.
So send it.
Kidnappers must have seen
Ian's "Proof of Life" Coin
and turned their
burners back on.
Just in time.
It looks like they
are about to respond.
Okay. here we go.
Lucas.
please give them the money.
They said they're gonna kill me
if you don't give them
the money.
Okay. time stamp
on that news clip
is from one minute ago.
Turn that station on.
[suspenseful music]
Is that... yeah.
- Yeah. that's live.
We can still save this girl.
Okay. so where are
they holding her?
The burner that they're using
doesn't have GPS services on.
and they stripped all location
metadata from the video.
She's in a pretty
nondescript room.
Hang on.
That structure
is a round masonry heater.
Uh. that kind of brick design
with a small firebox.
that's really unusual.
It's German style.
circa 1900 to 1915.
You're up on 20th century
masonry now. Moran?
I helped my uncle renovate
a building one summer.
Would you let the man cook?
Most owners ripped
these out by the '90s
because of the city's updated
Air Pollution Control Code.
but the ones that didn't
need to file permits.
Elise.
- Yeah.
There can't be many
of those things left.
Searching Department of
Buildings records for Section...
- 21.
- 21 masonry permits.
filtering by year and style.
Okay.
And then there were four left.
Yeah. we'll split the team.
We'll narrow it down
on the ground.
♪ ♪
Okay. SWAT's still
a few minutes out.
Maggie and OA cleared
the other two buildings.
So you've got a 50/50 shot
with this one.
Just proceed with caution.
♪ ♪
We're in the right place.
Confirmed. Jubal. this is
where Faith was being held.
Copy that.
[indistinct Russian chatter]
- It's almost time.
We gotta go.
♪ ♪
- All right. I count two...
armed.
Any eyes on Faith?
- Negative.
We gotta confirm
that Faith is on site.
Copy. Going right.
♪ ♪
[gunshots]
Go. go. go.
- Got him?
- Go!
[intense music]
♪ ♪
[buzzer blares]
[tires squeal. engine revving]
OpCen. two male suspects
fleeing north on DuPont.
black Dodge Challenger.
Couldn't get a plate.
Put out a BOLO now.
So... so two kidnappers
got away.
One was killed.
What about
Lucas Williams's sister?
No. Eva and Scola
swept the property.
She was not there.
So we don't know
if she's alive or dead.
No. but we're
digging into the perp
that our team took down.
How we doing. Elise?
Yep. Simon Brumel. 20 years old.
No gang affiliation.
just minor drug possession.
assault charges
for a couple bar fights.
It's a big leap
from drunk and disorderly
to murder and kidnapping.
- Got something.
Simon wasn't affiliated.
but looks like his father was.
He's Bratva?
♪ ♪
Why are you sweating. man?
We'll be there.
- You lied to me.
- Go to another room.
Faith Williams' kidnappers.
they... they work for you.
You really thought
I wouldn't figure it out?
You're not that slick.
Do not mistake our history
for permission to disrespect me.
I'm starting to question
our history altogether.
What are you doing. man?
She is a child.
I did not order this.
- No?
We ID'd one of the kidnappers.
The name Brumel ring any bells?
Brumel's boy does not
work for me.
None of those kids do.
I heard whispers
about these kids.
they're trying to make
a reputation. to get noticed.
Well. they did. just not
so much how they hoped.
And I found out
only after you came here.
I don't know where
they're holding the girl.
♪ ♪
Prove it.
Help me save her.
♪ ♪
[tense music]
Thank you.
Thank you. Robin.
[sighs] You want some?
Still eating like
a 14-year-old. I see.
Old habits. I know.
It'll be the death of me.
[chuckles]
Trust. Jubal.
I asked these kids to meet.
They'll come to me.
Andrei's intel helped us
identify these two men
as our kidnappers...
Nikita Kharkov and Ilia Marinov.
They're practically kids.
If they spook and they
don't show up. we have nothing.
Having a face-to-face
with Andrei means something.
If they're trying to move up.
this is their chance
to impress the boss.
They think recovering
Andrei's 300K
will make them invaluable
to Bratva.
Okay. Jubal's wire is hot.
He and Andrei are gonna get
them to incriminate themselves.
then we will arrest them
and use that information
to see if we can get
Faith Williams' location.
Andrei could have
something planned here.
Are we sure we trust him?
No.
Oh. showtime.
Hey. Jubal.
we have a car pulling up now.
Is it the black Dodge we
last saw the suspects driving?
No. it's a green BMW.
Okay. we got a problem.
Nikita's the only one
that showed up.
That means that Ilia
might be with Faith
at a different location.
I think it's gonna put her
in danger
if we arrest Nikita here.
What I think you should do
is get Nikita
to say the location
where they're holding Faith.
And whatever you do.
make sure that Nikita
and Ilia don't speak.
♪ ♪
- Here he comes.
[clears throat]
Mm. Mm-hmm. Da. Da.
♪ ♪
You wanted my attention.
You have it.
We figured out who robbed you.
Did I ask you to do that?
Do I know you at all?
No.
But I know you.
I could be an asset to you.
Make sure no one steals
from you ever again.
So where's my money?
I'll have it in...
90 seconds.
How... how much?
All of it.
315.000 in Bitcoin.
Is it me. or are you also
feeling a little doubtful here?
I mean. why is this...
why is he so confident
that the money's
gonna come through?
[speaking Russian]
I'm the accountant. Okay?
He is part of Bratva.
unlike you.
Answer his question.
We're not stupid. okay?
We have the sister
as collateral.
You don't get your money
by 5:00 p.m.. we kill her.
Okay. well. I hate to break
it to you. but it's 5:00 p.m..
so where is it?
I see no money.
♪ ♪
[sighs] We'll show
the thief we're serious.
Ilia will finish the job.
- No. no. no.
No. no. stop. stop. stop. stop.
You kill that girl.
my boss doesn't
get his money. all right?
You need to tell us
where she is.
Hey. I said stop.
You need to tell us
where the girl is right now.
- Let go of me!
I can handle this. okay?
[slams table] Enough.
Tell me where the girl is
before your stupidity
brings us all down.
The real men will
clean up your mess.
You're gonna wanna check
how you talk to me. old man.
I'll be running Bratva one day.
Kid...
you will never be a part
of my organization.
♪ ♪
[grunts]
Damn it.
[scream]
[grunting]
[clattering]
- FBI.
- Let me see. Let me see.
We need a medic in here!
- It's over. Nikita.
- Get off me!
Where is Faith Williams?
Huh?
You better pray that
that girl is still alive.
Where is she. Nikita? Tell me!
Maggie. Ilia is two blocks
north in the Dodge Challenger.
He has Faith.
Copy. We're on our way.
♪ ♪
[gunshots]
Don't shoot.
She's in the trunk.
I could skip a round.
Okay. well. don't miss.
FBI! Drop your weapon!
[gunshot]
- [yells]
Go. Go. go.
- [groaning]
- I got him.
Hey. Faith.
[groans]
You're okay.
- [whimpers]
- Hey.
Where's Lucas?
Where's my brother?
I want my brother.
- We've got him. Faith.
He's safe.
Come on.
- Is he okay?
- He's okay.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
[crying]
Such a tragedy. right?
Kid just made one bad choice
after another.
He was just trying
to save his family.
- Dad is dead.
He's going to prison.
That girl is gonna end up
in foster care.
I wish this one
had a happier ending.
[sighs] Yeah. me too.
They are both still young.
You know. with early parole
and the right support system.
maybe it's not too late
for Lucas to make
different choices.
I'd like to believe that.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
[crying]
[sighs]
Some things never change. Jubal.
I can hear you
thinking from in here.
[chuckles]
I couldn't tell
if you were awake.
I am glad you're gonna be okay.
It'll take more than this
to bring me down.
Today was almost like
the old days.
That's your idea
of a good time. huh?
Well. speaking of the old days.
I brought you something.
Remember our little
side business in Moscow?
Stealing pastila
from the school comms
and selling it to the rich kids
at twice the price.
[laughs]
It was a nice
little scheme. huh?
- Yeah.
[chuckles]
We were always a good team.
Yeah. we were.
How long are you gonna be
in New York for. you think?
I'm sure someone in your
office can answer that for you.
It's not too late.
[sighs]
I know... I know
it wouldn't be
exactly how we planned. but...
I could help you actually
get out.
You have to work with me.
We can make it happen.
I know what you're saying.
I. too. am happy to
see you again. Jubal.
But...
[sighs]
Next time we meet.
I do not expect
it will be as friends.
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Get well soon. Andrei.
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
[wolf howls]